坎尼尔·奥提斯 他在和伊斯兰国合作
Kaniel Outis. He's been working with ISIL.
你知道迈克尔不可能干那些事
You know that's not Michael.
我们之后还需要你
We're gonna need you.
死了就能好好休息了
I can rest when I'm dead.
那也是我担心的
That's what I'm worried about.
我不会丢下迈克尔的
I'm not leaving Michael.
但我们不能为了一个人 拿这一切冒险
We can't risk all of it for just one man.
伊斯兰国攻破了检查站
ISIL has broken through the checkpoint.
萨那城已经沦陷了
Sana'a is falling.
不合作 咱们都得死
We work together or we both die.
我保证
You have my word.
阿布·拉马尔才是波塞冬想放出来的那个人
It's Abu Ramal that Poseidon wants free.
波塞冬派你来的吗
Poseidon sent you?
住手
Enough!
他到底是谁
Who the hell is this guy?
-我哥哥  -你怎么又进监狱了...
- He's my brother. - Back at the prison...
我必须否认... 你在 你在拍我
I had to deny... you were, you were filming me.
他们不能知道
and they can't know.
阿布·拉马尔已经被杀了
Abu Ramal has been martyred.
整个伊斯兰国军队
The entire army of ISIL
向我们宣战了
just declared war on us.
看看这大反派
Behold the villain.
我进城买点咖啡
Hey. I, uh, I ran into town to get some coffee.
-你要什么吗  -不 不需要
- Do you want anything? - No. I'm good.
谢谢你亲爱的 我这边马上结束了
Thanks, honey. I'm almost done here.
我马上就到湖那边找你 好吗
I will see you at the lake in a little while, okay?
好 回家见
Okay. I'll see you back at the house.
你丈夫吗
The hubby?
你从凯勒曼那边发现什么了
Uh, what did you learn from Kellerman?
真是难以启齿 亲爱的
There's no easy way to deliver this news, darling.
你会心碎的
It's a heartbreaker.
并不是什么好消息
Doesn't get any better.
他坏到骨子里了
He's rotten all the way to the core.
你一直跟敌人同床共枕
You've been sleeping with the enemy, baby.
我不明白
I don't understand.
这两个鬼杀了凯勒曼之后
I followed them two monkeys from Kellerman's house
我从凯勒曼家里一直跟踪他们
right after they put a bullet in him.
不用说他不是我们要找的人
Needless to say he wasn't our guy.
不过他的确警告了我们
He did say some pretty alarming things
关于你儿子 波塞冬 世界混乱制造者
about your boy, Poseidon, the world shaker.
信息不够 我难以理清头绪
Didn't give me enough to put all the pieces together.
等等 倒回去 他们说了什么
Back up, back up, back up. What did they say?
雅各布 他说了什么
Jacob? His words?
我接近不了 没听到多少 但我的确...
I couldn't get close enough to hear much, but what I did...
听到了你和迈克尔的名字
what I did hear was your name and Michael's.
对 他们看上起很惬意
Yes, they seemed pretty cozy,
-他们三个  -我的天呐
- the three of them. - Oh, my God.
肯定是在暗中密谋... 你去哪儿
It's a nasty bag of conspire... Where are you going?!
去找我儿子
To my son!
蹲下来 蹲下来
Stay down. Stay down.
又是一次炮火攻击
It's another artillery strike.
他们肯定都习惯了
But they sure as hell are used to it.
跑 跑
Go, go!
真主伟大 真主伟大
Allahu Akbar. Allahu Akbar.
真主伟大
Allahu Akbar.
伊斯兰国刚刚悬赏了一千万要我们的人头
ISIL just offered ten million for our heads!
等等 等等 待在这儿
Wait. Wait. Stay here.
我们不能呆在这儿 不然就死定了
We got to get off these streets or we're dead.
一千万伊朗币
Ten million rial?
这么多钱 卖了你妈都愿意
You give up your mother for cash like that.
弗雷迪·墨库里的骨灰差不多这个价
It's about what I paid for Freddie Mercury's ashes.
现在说有意思吗
Freddie Mercury now, really?
总比讨论50万人
It's better than talking about 500,000 people
追杀我们好
looking to kill us.
快点
Come on.
找个地方躲起来想想下一步怎么办
Found a place to figure out next steps.
我们走
Let's go.
现在你告诉我到底发生了什么
This is the part you tell me what's going on,
整件事情
the whole thing.
不 没 没时间
No. Th-There's no time.
这国家要完了
Country's about to fall.
我保证之后会告诉你的
You'll get your answers, I promise.
现在我们别无出路
Right now our window is closing.
我们得...
We need to...
得转移到下一个应急点
We need to pivot to the next contingency.
-去火车站  -到北边去
- Train station. - Get up to the north.
从北离开这个国家
Exit the country that way.
你在奥杰吉厄岛监狱这四年
Things have changed in the four years
事情已经变了 迈克尔
you've been locked up in Ogygia, Michael.
你的计划没用了
Your plan's redundant.
伊斯兰国控制了北方 公路 检查点 火车站全部控制了
ISIL control the north, roads, checkpoints, train stations.
即使能穿过城 出去等于自杀
Even if we make it across the city, it's suicide.
不 你错了 这是金蝉脱壳
No. You're wrong. It's a shell game.
最危险的地方就是最安全的地方
You go where they never expect you.
等等 你大老远跑来也门找他
Wait. You came all the way to Yemen looking for him.
你以为他失踪了还是怎么了
You think he was lost or something?
说说
Come on.
你想活下去吗
You want to live?
机场是唯一的选择
The airport's the only option.
机场是通往外面世界的主要通道
The airport's known as the main artery to the outside world.
伊斯兰国肯定最先关掉机场
It's the first thing ISIL will shut down.
飞机一小时前飞走了 你有电话吗
Planes were flying an hour ago. You got a phone?
没有 但他有
No, but he does.
虽然是对着手机自慰
Burned it up jacking off to Queen, though.
我承认了
Guilty as charged.
我们说好了 C-Note在飞机上找到一条通道
C-Note's organizing a passage on the flight as we speak.
不 我告诉你
No, I'm telling you,
我的计划会成功的
my plan will work.
一旦... 一旦离开
Once... once you leave
萨那北部...
the northern part of Sana'a...
够了 我们根本不该讨论这些
Enough. We shouldn't even be talking about this.
放开我
Get off me!
你为什么还活着
How are you alive?!
跑到也门来了
In Yemen?!
究竟发生了什么 迈克尔
What happened to you, Michael?!
你要是不跟我说清楚我一步都不走了
Now, I'm not moving another inch until you tell me
这里到底发生了什么
what the hell is really going on here.
迈克尔·斯科菲尔德必须死
Michael Scofield had to die.
我必须假装自己死了
I had to fake my death.
然后离开
Go away.
这是交易的一部分
It was part of the deal I made.
如果我为卧底特工工作
If I went to work for a deep-cover operative
波塞冬...
named Poseidon...
我们都会自由
we would all go free.
我们已经自由了
We were free.
我们已经被赦免了
We were exonerated.
不 那只是我们以为的...
No. That's what we thought...
但我们错了
but we were wrong.
我跟萨拉结婚前几周
A few weeks before I married Sara...
波塞冬找到了我
I was approached by Poseidon.
你觉得我在炫耀吗
You think I'm showing?
我还没习惯
I'm not used to that yet.
我得... 我得告诉迈克尔
I got to... I got to tell Michael.
给你
Here you go. Burgers will
-汉堡马上就到  -你好
- be just a second. - Hello?
对 我是迈克尔
Yes, this is Michael.
波塞冬告诉我凯勒曼没有权利
Poseidon told me Kellerman didn't have
赦免我们的罪行
the authority or jurisdiction to exonerate our crimes.
他拿这件事当成筹码
He used that as a legal fulcrum.
跟我说他能把我们所有人
Told me he could put us all away for life
绳之于法 除非...
within the mandate of the law unless...
除非我为他工作
unless I went to work for him.
他们他妈的怎么能
What the hell can they be talking about
在这种时候聊天
at a time like this?
我不知道...
I don't know...
不过哥俩到底在说啥 我也想知道
but big brother's hearing things I want to hear.
我们不能留在这儿
We cannot stay.
得马上离开
We must go now.
也许不用
Maybe we don't.
你他妈说什么呢
What the hell are you talking about?
也许所有的逃跑
Maybe all this running
不过是延长死期
is just delaying the inevitable.
不是独自死在这儿 就是在家孤独终老
Die alone here. Die alone at home.
你该找个女朋友
God, you need a girlfriend, man.
有声音靠近 他们快找到我们了
Those voices are heading our way. They're almost on us.
这波塞冬是谁啊
Who the hell is this Poseidon guy?
一个神经病
A psychopath.
一个失望的中央情报局政策研究人员
A frustrated policy wonk in the CIA
他觉得自己比上级更强
who felt he could do better than his superiors.
他在中情局造了个细胞叫空洞二一
So, he created a cell within the CIA called 21-Void,
来实行他自己的智能手术
implementing his own intelligence operations.
他找我帮忙
And he needed my help
把囚禁在世界各个角落的人带出来
breaking out people imprisoned all over the world.
恐怖分子
Terrorists,
反党者
political dissidents...
流氓劫匪...
rogue agents...
如果我照做 你和萨拉 你们都能自由
and if I did it, you and Sara, you'd go free.
你的前科记录可以删除
Your record's expunged,
但是... 我们有过争执
but... there was a rub.
他不允许我联系你们
I wasn't allowed to have contact with any of you,
儿子也不行
including my son.
迈克尔
Michael.
所以 迈克尔·斯科菲尔德死了...
So, Michael Scofield was dead and...
我用不同的假名字过了很多年
over the years I assumed many names.
坎尼尔·奥提斯 最新的一个
Kaniel Outis... the most recent.
为什么你不告诉我
Why didn't you tell me?
为什么不联系我
Why didn't you reach out to me?
我无从选择
I didn't have a choice.
波塞冬做得很... 决绝
Poseidon made that... very clear.
怎么说
How?
一开始 我拒绝了
At first, I said no.
我不想帮他
I wouldn't do it.
没几周 萨拉就被监禁 挨打
Then within weeks, Sara was incarcerated, beaten.
我就答应了
And so I gave in.
我做的一切 都是为了家人
Everything I did, I did for family,
为了你 为了萨拉
for you, for Sara,
为了迈克... 为了让你们远离监狱的生活
for Mike... so none of you would ever have to spend another day
不用过着逃亡的日子
inside a prison cell or... or live a life on the run.
看看我们现在
Look at us now.
他们开始搜查房屋了
They're starting to search the buildings.
-去火车站  -机场
- Train station. - Airport.
火车站
Train station.
所有旅客必须出示机票
All passengers must present a ticket.
这样可上不了飞机 我们得穿过去
Never gonna get to our seats. We need to go through there.
机长都坐不上飞机
Even the pilot can't get on the plane.
这个飞机场停满了飞机
This is an airport full of planes.
-总会有别的机长 -情况不妙
- There's got to be others. - It's no good.
今天大家会死在这里
People will die here today.
再想个办法
We need another option.
-找我的人 奥马尔  -奥马尔
- My man, Omar. - Omar?
那个狡猾的家伙
That slippery brother?
信任是奢侈品
Trust is a luxury right now.
在这点上 他值得信任
He can be trusted. To a point. He has connections on
-他能联系桑西部海岸 带我们穿过沙漠  -不行
- the western coast, across the desert. - No.
林肯和迈克尔还在路上 这才是计划
Lincoln and Michael are coming here. That's the plan.
如果我们离开 他们就无处可逃了
They don't have a next move if we leave.
现在他们还在外面 天知道在哪里
Now they're out there somewhere, God knows where.
你的朋友们来得太迟了 看看你周围
Your friends are too late. Look around you.
这机场对他们没好处
This airport is no good to them.
我们不走
We're not leaving.
你们要去哪儿
What is that place?
西方人逃出来
Where the westerners went
去哪里了
when they made their escape.
我去过一个窝点
I ran into one at the Forger's Den.
我能帮上忙
I can help.
你个独眼龙
And how do you expect to find the foreigners
怎么找外国人
with only one eye?
他们来了 伊斯兰国的来了
They're here. ISIL are here!
过来 跟我来 我有主意
Come on, come on. I have an idea.
机长
The pilot.
跟我来 跟我来
Okay, follow me. Follow me!
别跟丢 别跟丢了机长
Don't lose him. Don't lose the pilot.
快点 快点 快点
Come on. Come on, come on.
快快 快点跑
Come on, come on, come on, come on.
别太高 猫下身体
No, just stay down.
好 在这等我
Okay. Wait here.
-什么  -马上回来
- What? - I'll be back.
-本杰明...  -别跟来
- Benjamin... - I'm going alone.
别去
Don't do it.
站住
Halt!
你在这里做什么
What are you doing here?
-跪下  -别动
- On your knees! - Halt!
出来 出来
Come out. Come out.
你是谁 证件呢
Who are you? Papers.
-别开枪 别开枪  -证件
- Don't shoot. Don't shoot. - Papers.
异教徒
Infidels!
异教徒在机场里
The infidels are in the airport.
杀了拉马尔的凶手 我亲眼看到了
The killers of Ramal! I've seen them with my own eyes.
-什么  -我要报酬
- What? - I want my reward.
一千万里亚尔 我要有钱了
The ten million rial. I will be rich.
-带我们去  -除非你保证
-Take us to them. - Not until you promise
我能拿到一千万里亚尔
I will get my ten million rial.
如果是真的 你会拿到这笔钱
If you speak the truth, you'll have the money.
你打了很多无辜的穆斯林
You kick a lot of ass for a good Muslim.
人是活的 路是死的
You can take the man out of the streets,
既然没有别的路 只能杀了拦路人
but you can't take the streets of the man.
你为什么帮我 你是谁
Why do you help me? Who are you?
我和你一样
I'm a man, just like you,
想逃开这个鬼地方
trying to get out of this madness,
可我们没法从那些门出去
but we're not gonna get out through those gates.
现在出去的唯一方法
The only way out now
是飞机 哥们儿
is up, brother.
波音747没法用
The 747 is done.
已经被叛军包围了
It's been secured by the rebels.
我不是说也门航空
I'm not talking about Yemenia Air.
我看上的
I have my eyes
是另一架
on a different set of wings.
妈妈
Mom?
萨拉
Sara!
太突然了
You scared us.
-抱歉  -一切都好吗
- Sorry. - Is everything all right?
好 一切都好 我只是... 今天有点凌乱
Yeah, no, It's fine. I just... it's been a crazy day,
差点忘了迈克要上西语课
made more so by the fact that I forgot Mike's Spanish lesson.
-西班牙语  -对
- Spanish? - Yeah.
-不是今天  -我们车上说好吗
- That's not today. - We're gonna talk about it in the car, okay?
你确定吗 真的没事吗
Are you sure? Is everything okay?
真的 我们没事 谢谢
Really. Yes. We're fine. Thank you.
我去拿迈克的包
Well, let me get Mike's bag.
不用了 放着吧 我明天来拿
No, no, don't worry about it. I'll get it tomorrow.
不管发生什么都别下车
I want you to get in the car and no matter what...
别出来好吗
You don't get out, okay?
你急匆匆地要去哪里
Where you going so fast?
进去
Get in.
谢谢
Thank you.
昨天的部门会议怎么样
How was that department meeting yesterday?
你经常见杀手吗
You usually meet with killers?
萨拉 比激动 听我说
Sara. Sara. Please, please, please.
我能解释 好吗 听我说
I can explain, okay? Just listen to me.
我受够了担惊受怕
I was sick with worry.
我得保护你 保护我们的家庭
I needed to protect you, to-to protect our family,
所以我从店里拿着你的手机
so I picked up your phone from the shop
带给安德鲁·纳尔逊
and I took it to Andrew Nelson,
我有个朋友在计算机科学系
my buddy in the computer sciences department.
他深度调查了
He did a deep dive,
什么数据探索之类的
some kind of data archaeology, and he did it.
他查到了那些混蛋的位置
He tracked those bastards down.
和联系方式
Got their cell information.
所以我就联系了他们
So... so I called them,
我以为可以
thinking I could... I could maybe
-跟他们谈条件  -你居然给他们打电话
- make a make a deal with them. - You called them.
萨拉
Sara?
萨拉 求你了 听我解释
Sara, please, listen to me.
萨拉 我是为了你啊
Sara, this was for you.
起开 别挡路
You're gonna want to get out of the way right now.
萨拉 萨拉
Sara. Sara!
到了
This is it.
这是我们逃出去的机会
Our ticket out of the country.
我跟你说迈克尔 这主意可馊
I'm telling you, Michael, this is a bad idea.
到处都是伊斯兰国的人
ISIL are everywhere.
不 我能做到
No, I can do this.
你真的花了一千万里亚尔
You really paid the equivalent of ten million rial
买人的骨灰吗
for some dude's ashes?
那可不是普通人 兄弟
Not just any ashes, man.
那可是弗雷迪·墨库里[皇后乐队的主唱]
Freddie Mercury's ashes.
翻两倍我也愿意买
I would've paid twice that.
走了
Come on.
低头
Keep your head down.
我们别再疯了 该去机场了
I think it's time we get sane and head to the airport.
不 不行
No, no, no.
这儿更好 他们控制着机场
This is better. They control the station.
最危险的地方就是最安全的地方
They'll never think to look for us here now.
火车是用来运货的
They're repurposing those trains for cargo,
不坐人
not passengers.
我们一旦上去了 就...
Once we're on, it's...
就是一路向北
it's a straight shot to the north.
他们不会再检查车厢
They won't check the cars again.
你见着火车就想到这些?
That's what you see when you see the train?
我只看到一堆拿着突击步枪的
I see a bunch of dudes with AK-47s
异国人 你真的以为
who don't look a thing like us. You really believe
咱们能逃上火车跑300英里吗
we can survive 300 miles on a train
还要穿过伊斯兰国的地盘呢
through ISIL territory?
这根本是自杀
Now that's suicide.
是有风险 不开玩笑
It does seem risky. No kidding.
不行
No, no.
只要上到那些车厢里 别抬头
We get in that line of cargo carriers. Keep our heads down.
上车后全程小心翼翼就好
Once we're on the train, lay low the rest of the trip.
再说了 我们不用跟他们一样
Besides, we don't need to look like them.
告诉那些信徒不要抬头
Tell the believing men to lower their gaze
并保持谦虚
and be modest.
快走
Come on.
可兰经的
From the Koran.
所有的路都封死了
All the roads are blocked.
所以得另辟蹊径逃去边境
So you'll have to find a different way to the border.
坐火车
By train!
希瑟 现在怎么办
Heather, what now?
什么怎么办
What now?
这就是个骗局 不是吗
I mean, it was all a lie. Wasn't it?
都是骗我的 我们的生活 婚姻
Everything. Our whole life, our whole marriage.
他和你都和我那么亲近
He was standing as close as you were to me right now,
他居然和射伤他的女人谈话
and he was chatting with the woman who shot him.
你是说他故意受伤
You're saying he planned to get himself shot
演给你看苦肉计吗
like it was some sort of, uh, sick performance?
我不知道 真的不知道
I don't know. I don't know.
就是 我...
I mean, I...
-对 对 就是那样  -但是他差点就死了
- Yes. Yes, it was. - But he almost died.
可能原计划是轻伤 对吧
So, the plan was to wing him, right?
只是为了让他洗清嫌疑 但是打偏了
To just put him above suspicion, but the shot went wide.
他被射中了
He gets hit.
-他知道自己娶了个医生 -萨拉 够了 停下
-He knows that he's married to a doctor.  -Sara, Sara, stop. Stop.
你已经三天没睡了吧
You haven't slept in three days, right?
那些人闯进你家
You're upset about the home invasion
你还得知自己的挚爱
and you're tying yourself up in knots
孩子的父亲 可能还活着
because the love of your life,
所以你很痛苦 很纠结
the father of your baby, might be alive.
林肯的电话也打不通
And I can't get through to Lincoln.
但是我看了视频
But I saw that video.
就是他
It's him.
- 好了 我...  -真的是迈克尔
- Okay, and I... - That's Michael.
我相信你 真的信
And I believe you. I do.
这很重要
And that matters.
这是最重要的
That's all that matters.
不 我知道
No, I know.
但雅各布是个好人
But Jacob is a good man.
他是你的丈夫
He's your husband.
-是啊  -他牵着你开始新生活
- Yeah. - And he helped you start a new life.
携手并肩
Together.
他来电话了
And that's him.
-我得接一下  -不 不要
- I have to answer it. - No. No.
-不要接  -请留言 稍后回电
- No, you don't. - Leave a message and we'll get back.
希瑟 希瑟 萨拉在你那儿吗
Heather, Heather? Is Sara there?
求你了 我想和她谈谈
Please, I-I need to speak with her.
这就是个误会
Look, there's been a huge misunderstanding
我能解释清楚的
and I can explain everything.
你能... 能告诉她吗
Will you just... Will you tell her that?
让她打给我
And to call me?
他在跟踪我
He's tracking me.
天啊 萨拉 亲爱的 我是你最好的朋友
Oh, Sara, honey. I'm your best friend.
他当然会先给我打了
Of course he's gonna call here first.
这不证明他是"深喉"
It doesn't make him Deep Throat.
我们该往好的方面去想
Listen, let's just see if there's a simpler explanation.
好
Okay.
他跟你说那个技术员叫什么
What was the name of that computer tech that he mentioned?
安德鲁
Andrew.
纳尔逊 安德鲁·纳尔逊
Nelson. Andrew Nelson.
好 我有个老朋友是那个部门的
Okay, well, I have an old friend in that department.
一通电话就能知道雅各布是不是在说谎
We can find out if Jacob's full of it in one call.
好的
Okay.
赶紧去火车另一边
Get on the other side of that train!
快 快跑 快点啊
Come on, come on, come on, come on, come on!
快快 咱们走
Come on, let's go.
你要干什么
What do you want?
看我给你发的照片
Look at the picture I just sent you.
我正看着那些杀人犯
I can see the murderers now.
他们在哪儿
Where?
先别急
Not so fast.
带上武器 我跟着他们
Bring your weapons, I will stay on them.
现在都听我指挥
And I call the shots now.
我们检查了 汽油足够我们飞出也门
We checked. There's enough fuel to get us out of Yemen.
问题是 你能把这老鸟飞上天吗
Question is, can you fly an old bird like this?
到时候就知道了
We'll find out.
萨那外30英里还有个车站
There's another station, 30 miles outside Sana'a.
我们可以在那里想办法上火车
We can find a way there, hop a train.
他们绝对想不到的
They won't anticipate us coming that way.
往一手烂牌上加注
Doubling down on a bad bet.
七年前你也做过 不过斗的是中情局
Just like you did seven years back with the CIA.
看看四周
Look around you.
你的计划连累了这么多人 自己还不知道
Your plans affect people, you don't even see it.
你怨我 我不怪你
I don't blame you for resenting me.
对 我就是怨你
You're damn right I resent you.
我知道 林肯 我懂
I see it, Linc. I see it.
每时每刻我都知道
Every second of every day,
那些被我牵连的人
the people, the collateral damage,
我害死... 的那些生命
the lives I've... affected.
但我不能想
But I can't start thinking about that.
要是一想
Because if I do,
就会崩溃 那我们都回不了家
then it all falls apart and none of us get to go home.
我必须要集中
I have to stay focused,
做个运筹帷幄的人
be the man with the plan.
就像在福克斯河监狱一样
Just like Fox River.
还记得么
Remember?
车子到手了
We got wheels.
干得漂亮
Good work.
去机场才是最佳选择
The airport's the only play.
机场只离我们八公里远
The airport is five miles away.
开去边界有一百六十多公里
The border is hundreds.
听着 机场可能是最佳选择
Look, the airport might be the right choice,
但我还是坚持我的直觉
but I trust my instincts.
他们关了我们这么久
They've gotten us this far.
直觉告诉我 我们能从北边逃走
And my gut says we can still make it out through the north.
看你们自己选了
Choice is yours.
就算你我跟你不熟 我也同意的你的意见
Look, man, I agree with you, even if I don't know you from Adam.
但是...
But...
既然马带你来这里你就应该继续跟着马出去 懂吗 所以...
got to go with the horse that got you here, you know? So...
他就是我的马
he's my horse.
这么疯的马我还从没见过
Craziest horse I've ever met.
但带我们走到了现在
But got us this far.
你是没死才敢说
Crazy only works
疯狂会起作用这种话
if it doesn't get you killed.
安德鲁
Andrew?
海登教授叫我们来跟你聊聊
Professor Hayden told us to speak with you?
对的 是我
Oh, yeah. Uh, yeah, right.
不好意思
Sorry.
你好 安德鲁
Hi, Andrew.
我是萨拉·斯科菲尔德
I'm Sara Scofield.
感谢你能抽出时间来
Thanks for taking the time.
能不能告诉我
By any chance,
我丈夫雅各布·尼斯请你研究我的手机了吗
did my husband Jacob Ness ask you to work on my cell phone?
有的 昨天叫的
Yeah, he did yesterday.
他叫你...
What did he, uh...
他叫你做什么了
What did he ask you to do?
他说他想找到是谁一直追踪他的妻子
Uh, he said he was looking to find the contact information
并且让我找出这些人的联系方式
for the people who were stalking his wife.
然后我就下载了份我能查到的数据给他
So I did a data dive and gave him what I could find.
怎么查到的
How?
他们黑进了你的手机并且留下了相关数据
They hacked your phone and lifted the data,
但在这一步骤里 他们留下了一个微小的电子签名
but in the process, left a very slight electronic signature
这样我就可以反向追踪他们
that I was able to track back to them.
等等 "他们"是谁
Wait, who are "They"?
我也不知道 是个虚假IP地址
Don't know. It was a dummy IP address,
但是手机信号和地址是对的
but the cell and location were correct.
在我面前这些都得显现原形
They couldn't hide that from me.
还是你老公
The man himself.
好啊
Hello.
萨拉 听我说 我知道你很伤心
Sara, listen, I know you're upset,
但我想你来趟惠特尼海茨警局
but I need you to come to the Whitney Heights police station,
现在
right now.
拜托你了
Please.
现在我们有时间可以聊聊了
So, now we got some time to talk.
你本名叫迈克尔
Well, your name's Michael.
行
Cool.
你有个哥哥
You have a brother.
还有什么是我不知道的
What else don't I know?
说真的 我想知道 我已经逃了这么久
Serious, I need to know. I've been traveling so fast,
目前为止 我一直在想你究竟是谁
for so long, I didn't even stop to think who you really are
或者在想我们究竟在这干什么
or what we're real doing here.
我甚至不知道
I don't even know why
为什么你要把我拉进来
you dragged me into all this, you know?
你得忘记过去的一切 维普 所有的事情
You got to forget the past, Whip, the details.
一切都不重要了
None of that matters now.
我在这几年做了些什么
What have my actions been all these years?
是谁一直在照顾你
Who's been taking care of you through everything, huh?
是我 对吗
Me. Right?
是不是
Right?
是啊
Yeah.
没有任何变化
Nothing changes.
你还是我的小鞭子
You're still my whip hand...
小鞭子 对 是你的小鞭子
Whip hand, yeah, I know, I'm your whip hand.
只是... 这次真不行了
It's... it's not good enough this time, man.
你能不能直说了
Can you just give it to me straight?
我是个成年人了 我能接受事实
You know, I'm a big boy, I can handle it.
你能成为我的小鞭子是有原因的
There's a reason you're my whip hand.
这个原因足以改变你的命运
A reason that's gonna change your life.
在旅途的终点有重大转折在等着你
There's a light at the end of the tunnel for you.
他妈的发生什么了
What the hell was that?
操他妈的
Son of a bitch.
我们得跑了
We got to go.
快跑
Let's go!
-没有路了  -医院的后门
- There's no way out. - Back of the hospital's
被石头堵住了 没有路
been shelled to rubble. It's blocked.
楼上也被封锁了
Upstairs is blocked, too.
我们去楼下
We're gonna go downstairs.
看看有没有路出去
Look for a way out.
你也一样
You do the same.
谢谢
Thanks.
发生什么事了
What's going on?
萨拉 你...
Sara, just...
你跟我们走
just come with us.
就知道发生什么了
You'll see. Please.
你好 女士 是萨拉·斯科菲尔德吗
Hello, ma'am. Um, Sara Scofield?
是的 警官
Yes, sir.
感谢您能前来 我是凯南警探
Thanks for coming in, I'm Detective Kennan.
我们想请你指认出闯进你家的嫌疑犯
We'd like you to point out who broke into your home.
然后...
And...
谁开枪打伤了你的丈夫
the one who shot your husband.
三号和四号
It's three and four.
那个男人和女人是枪手
The man and the woman was the shooter.
你确定吗
Are you sure?
我确定 警官
Yes, sir.
我十分确定
Yes, I'm absolutely sure.
这肯定有路能出去
There's got to be a way out.
肯定有... 有链接路面的通道
Something... something that connects to the surface.
往下走没有用的 迈克尔
Going down's not gonna work, Michael.
我们应该直接设埋伏 然后奋起反击
We need to set up an ambush and fight.
打架是你的惯用方式
Yeah, well, fighting is your default setting.
但不用总这样
It's not always about fists.
那我就这么跟你说 这里没有路出去
I'm telling you, there's no way out.
那就找些能打架的东西 你个蠢货
Then find something to fight with, you idiot.
这可不是什么轰趴
I don't think it's that kind of a party,
但我喜欢你的风格
but I like your style.
你想拿这个做什么
What are you going to do with that?
我也不知道
I don't know.
先给他们一下子
Beats a fist.
医用酒精吗
Rubbing alcohol?
你他妈的在干啥
What the hell are you doing?
你会瞎的 傻逼
You'll go blind, you idiot.
这只含百分之九十五的酒精
It's only 95% alcohol.
我只会瞎百分之九十五
I'll only go 95% blind.
这里 这里有个通风井
There. There's an air shaft.
好吧 现在要开始动拳头了
Well, it's about fists now.
迈克尔
Michael?
不好 他们来了
No. It's them.
我的初恋比我大很多
My first lover was much older than me.
他是我朋友的爸爸
He was my friend's father.
他叫玛希
Massi was his name.
这是我跟他之间的秘密
It was the greatest of scandals
也是最大的丑闻
that we kept to ourselves.
但他的妻子发现了我们的关系
But his wife discovered us
然后告诉了她的兄弟们
and told her brothers.
他们把玛希带去了沙漠...
Massi was taken into the desert...
然后把活埋了
and buried.
活活烧死的
Alive.
他们还用一块破布包着他的眼睛给了我
They brought his eyes to me in a rag.
我请求你用这个杀了我
I need you to use that on me.
结束我的苦难
End my suffering.
用这个吗
What, this?
贾 说得对 这些逃亡没有任何意义
Ja's right. All this running is pointless.
你知道到了那里 他们会对我做什么吗
Do you know what they will do to me here,
那些人
away from seeing eyes?
我做不到
I can't.
我不会让这发生的
I won't let that happen.
听见了吗
Do you understand?
我不会让它发生的
I won't let that happen.
听着 希德
Listen. Sid.
我不会放弃的
I'm not giving up.
和同性恋无关 你也不许放弃
And queer or no, you're not, either.
错的是他们
They're in the wrong.
不是你
Not you.
你准备用这做什么
What are you gonna do with that?
一次又一次 我付出所得
I've paid my dues. Time after time .
我已经服满刑期 但我并没有犯罪
I've served my sentence. But committed no crime...
迈克尔 拜托
Michael, come on.
对不起 林肯
I'm sorry, Linc.
我应该在你身边的
I should have come to you.
我不应该找你帮忙的
I should've asked for your help
当波塞顿跟我谈条件时 我搞砸了它
when Poseidon offered me the deal. I blew it.
当时 我想
At the time, I thought,
如果我自己能解决 那所有的痛苦都由我一人承担
if I dealt with it myself, the pain would only be mine.
但是相反 我打开的是潘多拉的盒子
But instead I opened this Pandora's Box.
我想要一切变好 但我只是让一切都变得更糟了
I wanted to make it better, but I only made it worse
对每个人
for everyone.
在那里...
And somewhere in there...
我变成了鬼魂
I became a ghost.
我犯了太多错误
I made a lot of mistakes.
做了太多愚蠢的 不完美的选择
A lot of foolish, imperfect choices,
但是每一个选择...
but every one of them...
我的每一次选择都是为了爱
every one of them I made for love.
我知道 我知道
I know. I know.
迈克尔
Michael,
你是我见过的最聪明的人
you're the smartest person I've ever known,
但你不能独自承担一切
but you can't carry the load on your shoulders alone.
我可以帮你分担
You need to share the burden.
嗯
Yes.
这才是家人
That's family.
这才是家人的意义
That's what family's for.
莎拉 我不知道你在想什么 但是...
Sara, I don't know what you thought, but...
我只是一个担心自己妻子的丈夫
I'm just a husband who was worried about his wife.
没错 我应该告诉你我在做什么 但是...
And yeah, I-I should have told you what I was doing, but...
听着 我感觉... 所有事都盘旋着
Look, I felt like... like everything was spiraling
超出了控制 我必须尽我所能保护你
out of control and I had to do whatever I could to protect you.
所以你觉得你能和两个雇佣杀手谈判
So you thought you'd contact two hired killers?
我只是想成为你的白衣骑士
I was trying to play the white knight.
虽然没有做好
Not very well.
而且这很疯狂
And it was insanity.
我害怕死亡
I was scared to death.
我真蠢
A blubbering idiot,
但我觉得他们想要的是钱 你明白吗
but I thought they would respond to money, you know?
给他们足够的钱打发走他们
Pay them whatever it took to make them go away.
超过他们的赏金
More than they were already making:
五万美金
$50,000.
听着 我...
Look, I, uh...
我放了追踪器在里面 莎拉
I had a tracker in it, Sara.
这块小东西 但是他们没有得到钱
This little thing, but they didn't touch it.
我在见面前联系了警察
I contacted the police before the meet,
但不管怎样 我们抓到了他们
but we nailed them anyhow.
我们抓到他们了
We nailed them.
雅各布
Jacob.
真的对不起 连累你经历这些
I am so sorry I put you through this.
动手吧
Let's do this.
一把扳手和一根钢管 对抗AK步枪
A wrench and a pipe against AKs.
会很有趣
It'll be fun.
我一直想砸烂这些杂种
I've always wanted a crack at these bastards.
♪我付出所得♪
♪I paid my dues♪
回来
Come back.
♪一次又一次♪
♪Time after time ♪
♪我已服满刑期♪
♪ I've served my sentence ♪
♪ 但我并没有犯罪♪
♪ But committed no crime ♪
♪严重的错误♪
♪ And bad mistakes ♪
到这来...
Get over here...
♪我是犯过一些♪
♪ I've made a few ♪
你会害死你自己的
You're gonna get yourself killed!
♪被人将泥沙♪
♪ I've had my share ♪
♪踢在脸上♪
♪ Of sand kicked in my face ♪
♪但我都熬过来了♪
♪ But I've come through ♪
♪我将会继续♪
♪ And I go on and on and on ♪
♪我们是冠军♪
♪ We are the champions ♪
♪亲爱的朋友♪
♪ My friends ♪
♪我们是冠军♪
♪ We are the champions ♪
♪ We are the champions... ♪
我爱你 你这狗养娘的日本疯子
I love you, you crazy Japanese son of a bitch!
是韩国人 兄弟
It's Korean, champ.
无所谓 我还是爱你
Whatever. I still love you.
伊斯兰国的人就像螳螂一样
ISIL are like roaches.
很快会有跟多人过来
More will be here soon.
我们现在怎么办
What do we do now?
我需要休息一下 再做决定
I need to take a break from making decisions.
林肯 机场那边呢
Linc, airport?
机场
Airport.
我找到了某个人 我想你们谈谈
I got someone I want you to talk to.
噢 兄弟
Oh, man!
我以为我再也听不到这个声音了
Now that's a voice I never thought I'd hear again.
你得解释一下了 兄弟
Man, you got some explaining to do, brother,
-你的死而复生  -很快
- risen from the dead and all. - Soon.
我们在哪碰面
Where can we meet you?
二号机库 主跑道右侧
Uh, hangar two. Right off the main runway.
但你最好快点
But you better hurry your ass up.
二号机库
Hangar two?
20分钟 我们能到那里
We could be there in 20 minutes.
我们20分钟后到
We can be there in 20 minutes.
我不知道是否能等那么久
I don't know if we have that long.
等我们 我们会到那
Wait for us. We'll be there.
我们得走了
We got to move.
希德...
Sid...
Sid!
我听到你的电话了 异教徒
I heard your call, infidel.
飞机不会带你们去安全的地方
Wings will not carry you to safety.
一个电话 我的兄弟们
One call, and my brothers
就会找到你们在机场的朋友
will find your friends at the airport.
-希德  -希德
- Sid!  - Sid!
操你妈
Son of a bitch.
不 不 不 不 不
No, no, no, no, no.
别死 希德 别离开我们
Talk to me, Sid. Stay with us.
别离开我们
Stay with us.
希德
Sid...
Sid.
他死了
He's gone.
别在他身上浪费时间
Don't waste yourself on him.
活下去随时都可以揍他
You'll beat him by surviving.
你们马上就会死 听见了吗
You will die, you hear me?
你们都会死
You will all die!
我的...
Oh, my...
他们把更多的卡车开到跑道上了
They're moving more trucks into position.
-嗯  -我们不能等了
- Yeah. - We can't wait.
没有足够的跑道起飞了 我们现在必须走了
There won't be enough runway to take off. We must go now.
我欠林肯一条命 他值得更好的生活
I owe Lincoln my life. He deserves better.
但是这么多生命在我们手里
But with so many souls in our hands,
我们真的有选择吗
do we really have a choice?
听着 我们再等五分钟
Listen, we wait five more minutes.
好吗
Okay?
到那时 我们只救走我们能救的人
And then we take care of the souls that we can.
明白了吗
Understand?
该死的 你在做什么
What the hell are you doing?
你到底在搞什么
The hell are you doing?
听着 我们不会丢下我的朋友的
Listen, we are not leaving my friends!
关掉它 关掉
Shut it down. Shut it down!
你会害死我们全部人
You would condemn us all to death.
如果你阻止我 没人能活着出去
If you stop me, no one gets out.
你的朋友能继续寻找安全的地方 但我们不行
Your friends can still make it to safety. We will not.
嗯
Yeah?
C-Note 你必须得走了
C-Note? You got to get out of here, man.
不 不 不 不 我们不能这么做 我们不能这么做
Hey, no, no, no, no. W-We can do this thing, man. We can do it.
不 现在就走 否则你和那些孩子都会死
No! Go now! Otherwise, you and the kids are dead!
我们会想办法的
We'll work something out.
不会更糟了
We've been through worse.
林肯 我很抱歉
Linc, I'm so sorry.
我真的很抱歉 兄弟
I'm so sorry, brother.
林肯 找到奥马尔 他...
Lincoln? Find Omar. He...
什么
What?
我听不见你说什么
I can't hear you. What?
电影淘淘
WWW.DYTTBD.COM
更多电影美剧尽在（电影淘淘 www.dyttbd.com）